[
    {
        "question": "If X represents the factors of production and Y represent the factor price, which of the following sets of association iscorrect?",
        "optionA": " (land, rent) (capital, wage), (labour, profit)",
        "optionB": " (land, interest) (capital,profit), (labour, wage)",
        "optionC": "(land, wage), (capital, interest), (labour, rent)",
        "optionD": "(land,rent), (capital, interest), (labour, wage)",
        "answer": "(land,rent), (capital, interest), (labour, wage)"
    },

    {
        "question": "If the cost of production for a firm continues to increase as it output rises, the firm is said to be experiencing?",
        "optionA": "diseconomies of scale",
        "optionB": "large-scale production",
        "optionC": "profit maximization",
        "optionD": "economies of scale",
        "answer": "diseconomies of scale"
    },

    {
        "question": "Who is Nigeriaâ€™s Minister of Education?",
        "optionA": " Adamu Adamu",
        "optionB": "Aja Nwachukwu",
        "optionC": "Ruqqayat Rufai",
        "optionD": "Mallam Ibrahim Shekarau ",
        "answer": "Adamu Adamu"
    },

    {
        "question": "Given perfect competition in the capital market, the opportunity cost of capital is adequately reflected by the?",
        "optionA": "returns on capital",
        "optionB": "shadow price of foreign exchange",
        "optionC": " interest rate",
        "optionD": "shadow price of foreign exchange",
        "answer": "returns on capital"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which of the following factors is an important determinant of the magnitude of price elasticity of demand?",
        "optionA": "DThe production period",
        "optionB": "Cost of storage",
        "optionC": "Durability of the product",
        "optionD": "Availability of factors of production",
        "answer": "Durability of the product"
    },

    {
        "question": "The marginal theory of distribution makes an assertion that the price of any factor depends upon its marginal?",
        "optionA": "utility",
        "optionB": "productivity",
        "optionC": "rate of substitution",
        "optionD": "revenue",
        "answer": "productivity"
    },

    {
        "question": "In order to increase its profit margin, the monopolist can manipulate",
        "optionA": "both price and output",
        "optionB": "only its output",
        "optionC": "only its price",
        "optionD": "either price or output",
        "answer": "either price or output"
    },

    {
        "question": "The merging of firmsengage in different stages of production and marketing is called?",
        "optionA": "economic unoin",
        "optionB": "external economies of scale",
        "optionC": " horizontal intergration",
        "optionD": "vertical intergration",
        "answer": "vertical intergration"
    },

    {
        "question": "which of the following is an important function of the retailer? ",
        "optionA": "Grant credit to the wholesaler",
        "optionB": "Breaks bulk and sales product in small units",
        "optionC": "Generates demand for production through advertisement",
        "optionD": " Reduces cost of distribution",
        "answer": "Breaks bulk and sales product in small units"
    },

    {
        "question": "One of the purposes of advertisement in marketing is to?",
        "optionA": " change the quality of the product",
        "optionB": "raise the quantity of the product demanded as its price falls",
        "optionC": "raise production cost",
        "optionD": "shift the demand curve for the product to the right",
        "answer": "shift the demand curve for the product to the right"
    },

    {
        "question": "The size of a business units tends to be small if the activity?",
        "optionA": "involves mass production of goods",
        "optionB": "requires a large capital",
        "optionC": "requires division of labour",
        "optionD": " involves the provision of direct services",
        "answer": " involves the provision of direct services"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which type of business organization has the attribute of effectively combining management with control?",
        "optionA": "sole proprietorship",
        "optionB": "Co-operatives",
        "optionC": "Partnership",
        "optionD": "Limited liability company",
        "answer": "sole proprietorship"
    },

    {
        "question": "the type of business finance that entitle the holder to a fixed rate of dividend is?",
        "optionA": "perferred stock",
        "optionB": "common stock",
        "optionC": "bank loan",
        "optionD": "debenture stock",
        "answer": "perferred stock"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which of the business organization listed below is characterized by limited authority and liability of the individual owners?",
        "optionA": "Co-operative society",
        "optionB": "Sole properitorship",
        "optionC": "Partnership",
        "optionD": "Joint stock company",
        "answer": "Joint stock company"
    },

    {
        "question": "The term 'double coincidence ' of wants is usually associated with a?",
        "optionA": "bilateral exchange mechanism",
        "optionB": "monetary exchange mechanism",
        "optionC": "stock exchange system",
        "optionD": "barter exchange mechanism",
        "answer": "barter exchange mechanism"
    }
]